brandfield.com 2018-12-16

# Privacy Policy

INFORMATION ABOUT

Privacy-sensitive data, or personal data, are processed via our e-store. Brandfield B.V. considers the careful handling of personal data to be very important, so we process and secure personal data accordingly.

When we process data, we comply with the requirements imposed by privacy laws. That means, among other things, that:

  * we clearly state the purposes for which we process personal data, and we fulfill this requirement via this privacy statement;
  * we limit our collection of personal data to those data necessary for legitimate purposes;
  * in cases where your consent is required, we first ask you for explicit consent before we process your personal data;
  * we take appropriate security measures to protect your personal data, and require the same of parties that process personal data on our behalf;
  * we respect your right to inspect, correct or remove your personal data upon your request.

Brandfield B.V. is the party responsible for processing the data. This privacy statement explains which personal data we collect and use, and for which purposes. We advise you to read it carefully.

## USE OF PERSONAL DATA

When you use our e-store we obtain certain information from you, which can include personal data. We only retain and use the personal data provided directly by you in the context of the service you request, or where it is clear that this data is provided to us for processing.

We use the following data for the purposes mentioned in this privacy statement:

  * name and address
  * phone number
  * invoice address
  * e-mail address
  * payment details
  * gender
  * date of birth

### REGISTRATION

Certain parts of our e-store require you to first register. After registration, we retain the personal data provided by you under your chosen username. We retain this data so that you do not have to enter it every time you return, and so that we can contact you in the context of execution of the agreement.

We will not pass on to third parties the data linked to your username, unless this is necessary in the context of executing the agreement that you conclude with us or if this is legally required. In the event of suspected fraud or abuse of our website, the personal data may be submitted to the competent authorities.

### ACCESS TO OUR PORTAL

Our portal gives you access to a management environment where you can set up, specify and change items yourself.

### PROCESSING YOUR ORDER

For the purpose of contract performance, we disclose your data to the shipping company in the scope required for the delivery of the ordered goods. Depending on the payment service provider you have selected during the ordering process, we disclose the payment details collected for order processing purposes to the bank commissioned to handle the payment and, as the case may be, to the payment service provider commissioned by us or to the selected payment service. Some of those data are collected by the selected payment service providers themselves if you open an account with them. In such a case, during the ordering process, you must register with your payment service provider using your access data. In this respect, the privacy notice of the relevant payment service provider applies.

### CONTACT FORM AND NEWSLETTER

Our e-store offers you the option of asking questions via a contact form, where you are asked to fill in various details to process your request. You decide which data you provide. The data you send us will be retained for as long as is necessary to completely respond and process your request according to the nature of the form or the content of your e-mail.

We offer a newsletter to inform those interested in our products and services. If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will regularly send you our e-mail newsletter based on your consent, using the data required or disclosed by you separately for this purpose. You may unsubscribe from the newsletter service at any time. For this purpose you can use the opt-out link in the newsletter. Upon unsubscription, we will delete your email address unless you have expressly consented to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your personal data in the scope and manner permitted by the law, of which we inform you in this notice.

### LOCATION DETAILS

If necessary for the service, we may collect location (GPS) data from you. Your consent will be required for this when the situation arises.

This location data can also be stored and processed by, for example, the provider of the navigation/map software, such as Google Maps, or by organizations such as Google or Apple. We have no influence on this. We recommend that you read the relevant privacy statements from the provider concerned.

### APP STORE

The app that provides the service is downloaded via an app store operated by a third party. We have no influence on which personal data the provider processes, and for what purpose. We recommend that you read the relevant privacy statements from the provider concerned.

### PUBLICATION

We do not publish your customer data.

### ADVERTISEMENTS

Our e-store displays advertisements.

### COOKIES

Our e-store uses cookies. Cookies are also placed by third parties engaged by us.

When you first visit our e-store, a notice is displayed in which we explain why we use cookies. If you continue to use our e-store, we will assume that you agree with this use of cookies.

You are free to disable cookies with your browser, but bear in mind that our website may no longer work fully.

We have made agreements with third parties who place cookies about the use of these cookies and applications. However, we do not have complete control over what the providers of these applications do with the cookies when they read them. For more information about these applications and how they deal with cookies, please see the privacy statements of the parties concerned (Note: These statements may be regularly modified).

In addition, please consult our comprehensive cookie policy.

### GOOGLE ANALYTICS

We use Google Analytics to keep track of how visitors use our e-store. We have signed a processor’s agreement with Google to establish arrangements concerning the handling of our data. We also allow Google to use the obtained Analytics information for other Google services and, finally, we anonymize IP addresses.

### SECURITY

We take security measures to limit abuse and unauthorized access of personal data. In particular, we take the following measures:

  * access to personal data is protected with a username and password;
  * we use secured connections (Secure Sockets Layer, or SSL) that protects all information exchanged between you and our website when you enter personal data;
  * we keep logs of all requests for personal data.

### RETENTION PERIODS

The personal data described above is retained for as long as is necessary to process your orders, including warranty. After that period, we store data for a maximum of one additional year for the statistical purposes described. The data will then be deleted unless there is a statutory obligation that requires longer storage, such as the seven-year fiscal retention obligation for payment data.

### WEBSITES OF THIRD PARTIES

This privacy statement does not apply to third-party websites that are connected to our e-store by hyperlinks. We cannot guarantee that these third parties handle your personal data in a trustworthy or secure manner. We recommend you read the privacy statement of these websites before using them.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy statement. We recommend you consult this privacy statement regularly so that you are aware of any changes.

### INSPECTION OF AND CHANGES TO YOUR DATA

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy or questions relating to the inspection, modification or removal of your personal data, you may contact us at any time via the details below.

If you wish to inspect the personal data retained about you by Brandfield B.V., or if you wish to change data because they are incorrect or incomplete, or want to have it removed or protected, please e-mail Marlies Monteban at Brandfield B.V. via info@brandfield.nl. Within four weeks Brandfield B.V. will inform you which personal data it processes about you and whether it will or can meet a possible request for removal, protection or correction.

To prevent abuse, we may ask you to identify yourself appropriately. If it concerns personal data linked to a cookie, you must also send a copy of the cookie in question. You can find this in the settings of your browser. If the data is incorrect, you may request that we change or remove it.

### DUTCH DATA PROTECTION AUTHORITY ('AUTORITEIT PERSOONSGEGEVENS')

Naturally, we are happy to help you if you have complaints about the processing of your personal data. Under privacy legislation, you also have the right to file a complaint with the Dutch Data Protection Authority against this processing of personal data. To do so, contact the Dutch Data Protection Authority.

### CONTACT DETAILS

Brandfield B.V.   
Stoelraaierstraat 70  
9712 BX Groningen  
The Netherlands  
customerservice@brandfield.com

This privacy statement was last modified on 01-01-2018..

## Any further questions?

Contact our [customer service](https://www.brandfield.com/customer-service/)
